ROSE WAN FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

rosexw.github.io

Toronto, ON

in rosexw

nosexw

I am a full-stack software developer coming from a chemistry and business background. I have a degree in Chemistry/English Literature, a postgraduate certificate in Global Business Management, and, most recently, a certificate in Full-Stack Web Development. I am a hard worker who doesn't give up until the project is completed. I love being able to mix in my artistic, with my analytical sides and am interested in front-end development. My most recent experience includes working on web and mobile applications with Evermiaht.

Skills

LANGUAGES

HTML/CSS/SASS

React

Ruby

Javascript

FRAMEWORKS

Meteor

Materialize Zurb Foundation

Bootstrap

Express

Rails

LIBRARIES

Redux

Node.JS

DATABASES

PostgreSQL

SQLite

SOL

MongoDB

SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING

TweetDeck

SEO

Facebook Pages

Web Analytics

Blog Writing

Buffer

Hootsuite

LinkedIn Instagram

Pinterest

Twitter for Businesses

Education

Lighthouse Labs

Certificate Web Development 2017

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp, Full Time

Rapidly learning new languages and skills & implementing them in intensive projects!

Humber

Postgraduate Certificate Global Business Management 2015

Marketing, Supply Chain, e-Commerce, Finance, Accounting, Project Management

University of Toronto

H.B.Sc Chemistry 2012

Organic, Inorganic, Analytical, Physical, Bio-Chemical Sensors, Specialized Courses

Projects

rosexw.qithub.io

Aug 2017 to Current

Created my own portfolio page. Simplicity is the key!

Jul 2017 to Jul 2017 Markets+

A farmer's market app so users can see products and markets close to them, and for farmers to communicate the products available and markets to sell at

This project is written with Ruby on Rails (1 week), React (1 week), and CSS/Material/SASS.

Snail Express lun 2017 to lun 2017

A hypothetical restaurant selling gourmet snails to test our knowledge with front end and back end, and uses PostgreSQL as our database

This was created with knowing very basic JavaScript to completing the product view, shopping cart adjustments, and user authentication in just four weeks!

Jun 2017 to Jun 2017

A Twitter imitation that uses our skills in HTML/CSS, JS, jQuery, AJAX in the front-end, and their Node, Express and MongoDB in the back-end

Employment

Evermight

Toronto Oct 2017 to Current

Junior Software Developer

Learned PHP, MySQL, and Wordpress on my own for a challenge.

Styled web and mobile pages in CSS/responsive design and React Native.

CCAB, a division of BPA

Toronto, ON

Apr 2016 to Mar 2017

Evaluated more than 5 audits at a time, kept track of upcoming audits with other circulation managers, and closed them in a timely manner.

RBC Toronto, ON Aug 2015 to Apr 2016

Processed payments in strict accordance to SWIFT, LVTS, CPA, FED, and RBC policy to the hourly requirements

Participated in the employee engagement committee as a volunteer

Toronto, ON

Apr 2015 to Nov 2016 Marketing Specialist

Managed social media accounts for a few of our clients, increasing engagement and followings by two or three times what it had started with

Wore different hats in public relations, recruiting and leading interns, live tweeting

Strengthened the efficiency of the company by researching strategies

Strong Nutrition and Weight Loss

Social Media Marketing Project Manager

Apr 2014 to Dec 2016

Expanded social media presence online to more than double or triple what they were

Contributed to blog posts, newsletters, canvas posters, and promotions

Started the new branding for Strong Nutrition and Weight Loss from Oakville Nutritionist

Volunteering

Start Up Open House · Volunteer Toronto, ON

Aug 2017 to Sep 2017

CMC (Circulation Management of Canada) · Social Media Manager

Nov 2016 to Aug 2017

Managed the company's Twitter, Facebook, and LinkedIn pages and keep members aware of current events.

Discover Your Personal Brand · Social Media Strategist Covered live tweeting from @DYPBTO for August 11-12, 2017

Aug 2017 to Aug 2017